Okay, so let's define quality.
It's very important to understand what the
definition of quality is.
Now, there are several definitions of
quality out there, but there's one
definition that you need to know for the
PMP exam.
This is a definition that PMI have adopted,
which is taken directly from ISO 9,000.
The definition states, quality
is the degree to which a
set of inherent characteristics
fulfills requirements.
So this is a definition that PMI have
chosen to adopt, taken directly from ISO
9,000, and this is a definition of quality
that is mentioned in PIMBOC.
It's a degree to which a set of inherent
characteristics fulfills requirements.
The degree to which your product meets
requirements.
And notice, the focus is on the word
requirement.
Notice there's nothing
in the definition that
states that the product
actually has to work.
All right, so let's explain this,
because this might be something different
to what you might have experienced or what
you are experiencing.
So a defect, a defect is that the product
does not meet requirements.
A defect is not the product doesn't work.
So let me give you an example here.
So let's say I'm in a room, So,
of course, there's four walls in this
room, and let's say, I'm your customer,
and I've hired you to paint this room.
And I give you a whole bunch of weird
colours.
I tell you, I want this wall bright
pink, this wall bright yellow,
I want this wall green, this
wall blue, I want the ceilings
purple, I want the
floors, and bright white.
And you say, are you sure about that?
I say, yep, this is exactly how I want my
room painted.
So you come along with all these color
swatches, and I sign off on them all.
those are my requirements.
I've signed off on them all.
So, you come along, you paint this room
exactly according to those requirements.
I walk in, I look around, and I think,
this is disgusting.
These colours don't work.
Now, I can't turn around to you at that
point and say, you did a poor quality job.
No, you followed my requirements.
You followed my instructions.
You met my requirements.
You painted the room exactly according to
the requirements I gave you.
So I can't turn around
to you and say you did a
poor quality job there,
these colours don't work.
I also can't turn around to you and say
this is a defect, these colours don't work.
No, because you followed my requirements.
So that is not a reflection on you doing a
poor quality job, if anything,
that's a reflection on me giving you a bad
set of requirements.
So quality always refers to whether or not
the product meets requirements
requirements, not whether or not the
product works.
So quality always refers to a defect,
always refers to the product meeting
requirements, not whether or not the
product works.
On the flip side of that, let's say you
delivered a perfectly working product,
but it doesn't meet the requirements.
That would be a defect.
So in the same example,
you've completely ignored all of
my colors and you painted it
one neutral color, that works.
But that didn't meet my requirements.
So that would be considered a defect.
So as another example then, let's say you
delivered a perfectly working car,
perfectly working car to a racing company.
It has everything in there, right?
It accelerates really well, handles really
well, really high top speed.
You deliver it to this race.
racing company, except they asked for a
motorcycle.
Even though you've delivered a perfectly
working vehicle, a perfectly working
product, they asked for a motorcycle,
not a car.
That would be a defect.
So always watch out for that in the PMP
exam.
It's not uncommon for you to get several
questions around this one definition.
always look at the word requirement or the
word that describes a requirement.
So even if they say, even if they throw a
curveball at you, let's say they say the
customer accepted it, you
deliver this product's not
meeting their requirements,
but they accepted it.
Well, it's still a defect, even though
they've accepted it.
I mean, for a start, you don't know why
They might have just have
accepted it to get rid of you
and now they're going to
bring in someone else to fix it.
Right?
So always, always watch out for that.
So quality is always whether
or not the product meets
requirements, not whether or
not the product actually works.
Now, along with this, there's another
definition, or rather another term that's
often used interchangeably with quality,
and that's this term called grade.
And so you need to know the difference
between grade and quality, right?
I mean, like I said, in reality,
we use those terms or we might use those
terms interchangeably, but There is a
subtle difference, right?
There is a difference between them.
And you also need to be
aware of the quality pioneer that
really promoted this term,
and this guy, Joseph Joran.
So he really promoted the difference
between grade and quality.
All right, so let's explain.
And the best way to explain this is really
to give you a little example.
So grade refers to things like the number.
of feature the product has, the type of
feature the product
has, customer perception.
So essentially, it's same functional use,
but different characteristics.
So it's a number of features, a type of
features, customer perception,
and so and so forth.
The best way to explain this is to give
you an example.
They've got a perfect example here.
So let's think of a car.
You've got a Toyota Camry versus an
expensive car like a Bentley.
So you purchase this really expensive car
like a Bentley and you know, it could last
you 10, 15 years without any problem or a
car like that.
But then you could also buy
Toyota Camry and that could
last you 10 or 15 years as
well without any problem.
So which is a better quality car?
So what you would say is this Bentley is a
high grade vehicle.
It's a high grade vehicle, has all the
bells and whistles, right?
It has all the luxury item.
And that's usually the best way to think
of grade.
Think of luxury items.
Whereas quality is, does actually do what
it's supposed to do.
So if you purchased this really expensive
Bentley and it kept breaking down,
that would be poor quality.
So in this case, then, this Bentley would
be a high grade, but poor quality.
Whereas, you could, you could.
could purchase a car like her to a Camry,
which would be considered lower grade,
you know, compared to a
Bentley, it would be considered
a lower grade, right, but
it could last you forever.
That would be good quality.
So that's the basic difference in between
grade and quality, right?
Grade is a number of features,
a type of features and customer perception
as well, whereas quality is, does it
actually do what it's supposed to do?
So one of the things, and amongst many,
many things, but one of the things that
Joseph Gerand was advocating
here when it came to grade and
quality, there's nothing wrong
in having a low-grade product.
All you're doing with
a low-grade product is
marketing it to a
different set of customers.
So grade just really refers to,
you know, essentially your customer base.
The more number of features the product
has, the higher the grade.
But the more number of feature the product
has, there's more for
things to break down.
and so poor quality is never going to be
acceptable.
So you should be focusing on quality
rather than grade.
So that's just one of the
things then that Joseph
Gerang was advocating,
amongst many, many things.
But just make sure,
though, you do understand
the difference between grade and quality.